Morning, Mr. King.
Morning, there.
Morning, Cecily.
How was your ride, Mr. McRae? Very good,
thank you.
Mrs. King?
Oh, hello, Stuart. How are you?
Listen, won't you stay for breakfast?
You two said I just made some fresh
coffee and a whole batch of scones.
Oh, thanks, Mrs. King, but no.
I've got a desk full of work waiting for
me.
I'll take a rain check, though.
Same here, Mrs. King.
Your whole family's been so good to us
since I lost Colleen.
I don't know what we would have done
without you.
Oh, Seth, it was the least we could do.
We all love calling dearly.
I know.
Thank you, Mrs. King.
Well, uh, like I said, I have to get
over to Carmody Station.
I don't think I have time to wait for
Felicity.
Oh, well, she'll be here in a minute,
but... Come to Aunt Janet, you big, big
girl, yes.
So how are you settling into the bank,
then?
Fine so far.
Enoch Kane left things in good order,
but it'll take me a while to get to know
the people as well as he did. Here's her
nappies, and this is her teddy.
She hollers blue murder if you put her
to sleep without it.
All right. Now you, be good. Oh, don't
worry about a thing, Seth.
How was he for you today, Mr. McRae? Did
the trick, Cecily, thank you.
Come on.
She's a wonder with the horse, that
girl.
Which reminds me.
Here's the two weeks' board that I owe
you, and something extra for Cecily. No,
you put your money away.
No, I insist. We made a deal. Forget it.
We should be paying you.
Having that horse to look after the last
few months has been a godsend for
Cecily.
After what we've been through the last
year, well, it's good to see one of my
daughters smiling.
I saw Felicity at the shore just now. I
didn't say hello.
She seemed so deep in thought.
She keeps vigil at the same spot every
morning at the crack of dawn.
Janet and I are worried sick about her.
Well, they say it takes time.
True, but it's been a year.
Seems that her life just stopped cold
when she lost Gus Pike.
Fred Billingsley. Long time.
Stuart, you old war horse.
You're looking prosperous these days.
Thank you kindly. I am.
What brings you to our neck of the
woods?
Come to plunder the locals?
I come bearing gifts.
I'm acting for the Lloyd estate.
Thought you could expedite a small
matter.
According to Miss Lloyd's will, there's
a house hereabouts that belonged to her
family.
Seems there are no heirs to squabble
over it, so she's left it to the town of
Avonlea. for a worthy and benevolent
cause.
It's your town, Stuart.
Pick one.
Well,
things don't work that way here in
Avonlea.
Miss Higgins, have Sally Potts start
calling around for a town meeting.
Tonight, seven o 'clock sharp.
Oh,
Alec.
Try to persuade Felicity to come with
us. That'll do her good. Mother, please.
already said no. Besides, Seth isn't
back yet. I'll stay with the baby,
Felicity. Just bring the baby, for
heaven's sake. Everybody else does.
You can't lock yourself away forever,
dear.
Please, just leave me be.
I would rather stay home.
It isn't healthy, you know.
Avoiding people, brooding.
She's becoming a hermit.
I know what Felicity is suffering.
I was just a girl when I lost my young
man.
The war, you know.
I mourned him far too long.
Is that why you never married Aunt
Eliza?
Yes.
I threw my young year away.
Pining for a boy who never came back.
I pray Felicity won't do the same.
Is everything all right?
Oh, yes, everything's fine. She's good
as gold.
Actually, we had quite...
Felicity, this is
Mavis. Mavis, this is Felicity King.
Mavis was Colleen's second cousin.
Felicity, I've been so looking forward
to meeting you.
Yes, it's nice to meet you too, Mavis.
Mavis and I have been writing to each
other for a while now.
She loved calling in dearly.
Mavis and I wanted you to be the first
to know.
Oh, boy.
We got married.
Married?
We were going to invite a few people,
but then we thought, well, maybe it's
better to do it just the two of us.
And Felicity.
I just know you and I are going to be
the best of friends.
Is Mr.
and Mrs. King here? We'd like to give
them the news.
They've gone to a town meeting.
Seth,
why don't we go too?
That way we can tell everyone at once.
Felicity, you must join us. It'll be
such fun.
I'll get the baby's things.
I've been aching to hold her.
Oh, yes.
They're in the kitchen.
Now, don't think unkindly of me,
Felicity.
It wasn't easy.
But the baby needs a mother, and Colleen
would have wanted that.
We're ready.
Come with me.
Please.
For my sake.
Make her feel at home.
Order, order. Give Mrs. Bugle a chance
to finish.
Well, I say that we should... I say that
we... I
say that we sell the house to the
highest bidder
and be done with it.
Let's use it as a clubhouse for the
Knights of PEI. Over, my dear buddy. I
that we convert the house into a
finishing school.
Yes, a finishing school for young
ladies.
Who wants a bunch of fancy society girls
running up and down the main street?
Carrying on and smoking cigarettes.
I vote for a guest house. Oh, it's so
absurd. We already have a hotel.
The last thing we need is more empty
beds. What about an art gallery?
Or a library?
Sell the place. Sell it? The place is
falling apart.
Nobody's lived in it for ten years.
You'd have to give it away.
Oh, it's probably crawling with mice and
raccoons.
Order, order.
Please, people.
I'd like to request a motion to form a
committee to check into the condition of
the house. It'll report back, and then
we can make a decision whether to sell
or keep it. I do. Thank you. Any
seconders? I'll second that motion.
Mr. King.
All those in favor?
All right.
Settled. Who besides myself would like
to serve on this committee?
I'll stand.
Then I will, too.
Forgive me for horning in.
I'm Mavis Pritchard.
Seth and I, we just got married.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
I've been so looking forward to becoming
a part of your community.
I was hoping I could get my feet wet by
joining your committee.
Well, good.
Very good.
And I'd like my new friend, Felicity
King, to serve with me.
No, no, I don't think so. I couldn't,
sir. Please, I won't take no for an
answer.
That's settled.
And heartiest congratulations to the
newlywed.
The first inspection of the house
tomorrow morning, 8 o 'clock sharp.
Thank you.
Your mother and I were...
Happy you volunteered tonight.
I didn't volunteer.
Mavis Pritchard pushed me into it.
How could he do it, Father?
Marry so soon.
Life goes on, sweetheart.
And it will for you, too, if you just
let it. Oh, Father, don't you see?
I'm in limbo.
If I'd seen him buried, if I knew,
but... Not like this, not ever knowing.
Well, we would have heard by now.
You've gone, Felicity.
I can't accept that.
I won't.
He's everywhere I turn.
He's a part of me.
How can I just dismiss him from my mind?
I let something, something else in.
Like Seth did.
Good morning.
Mr. McRae.
I've been waiting for you. I thought
perhaps we could walk over to the Lloyd
place together.
I don't think so.
That is, I wouldn't want to interrupt
your ride.
Not at all.
Blazers are under arrest, haven't you,
boy?
Besides, there's a shortcut that's
beautiful this time of the morning.
I'd like to show it to you.
It's just a bit further.
The morning light here is magnificent.
I like to think that I'm the only one in
the whole world who knows about this
spot.
Look. It is very beautiful.
I hate to disappoint you, though, but
Felix and Sarah and I used to play here
children.
I'd forgotten all about it.
Sarah loved to spin tall tales.
We'd pretend we were in a castle in
Spain. We built a...
Tiny stone cairns somewhere.
There it is.
We buried notes beneath it with secret
wishes for the future.
I can't believe it's still here.
Go ahead and dig it up, then.
I couldn't.
Why not?
Aren't you curious?
The future's now.
No, it isn't.
I don't believe in the future. It was
just a silly game.
Oh, there you are, Stuart MacLeay.
And Felicity Goode.
We may as well turn around and go home,
I'm afraid.
Oh, yes, that great antelope was quite
right.
The place is a disaster.
Nobody in their right mind would buy it.
Everything needs fixing.
I'm afraid it'll cost a fortune.
Mr. McRae, the roof's got to go. It's
leaking like a sieve.
Still, we shouldn't look a gift horse in
the mouth, I suppose.
Come on.
Oh, should we?
Let's be practical.
It's still a fine piece of land, and
with free labor from the community, we
turn this place around and reap a nice
profit from a sale.
Oh, it's a shame to sell it, though.
Look at the gardens.
I can imagine masses of lawn chairs. We
could open an old folks' home for ladies
of gentility.
Stop that nonsense, Olivia.
You'll not find me in a home for old
biddies.
Come on.
People are meant to grow old in their
own houses.
Come on.
Let's take a look inside.
What do you think?
Mouths or people?
Well, no mouth with a jaw that size.
You don't think real people are...
I
could be wondering.
Maybe we should call the others.
Hello?
Is there anyone up there?
are you?
Hold on. Calm down. What's going
on in here? Don't whip us. Whip you?
No one is going to whip you.
Back where?
Shut your gob, Duffy Dean.
It's okay, little fella. Nobody's going
to hurt you. You don't want to go back
where?
The orphanage. Now you've done it, I
told you not to tell nobody.
Oh, the poor wee thing.
Don't get so soft, Olivia.
There are rules about harboring
runaways, why they could be thieves,
the Lord knows what.
Well, we must at least inform the
orphanage and find out. No, no, no.
Stop it, everyone, please. Stop.
Can't you see that they are scared to
death? I think we should let them calm
down a little bit.
Well, I don't think that we need to
harass them either. What they need is a
hot meal.
Yes. I think so too.
How does that sound, little man? Are you
hungry? Don't listen to him, Duffy.
It's a trick.
Well, my mother's got some roast chicken
in the oven.
I could whip up some mashed potatoes
with lots of cream and butter.
There might even be some chocolate cake.
Chocolate cake?
Don't fall for it. They're a bunch of
liars. Thank God no chocolate cake.
Now that you're stuffed, how about
telling us your names?
I'm Duffy.
She's Bill Murray.
I'm Ollie. And who's Edgar?
It sure is good. Not a second.
Well, you're already on your third
piece, but who's counting?
Now, how did you end up at Gildedale?
It was on account of the Carmody flu.
We all got sick.
Only us kids got better, but our mom and
pop, they croaked. We ain't got no
relatives, so the trip is over to the
orphanage.
And it's as bad as you say?
They never have cake, and they're mean,
and they have bedbugs this big. The bad
part is they try to separate us, and I
swore to my ma we'd always sit together.
So you ran away and hid out in the
Lloyd's house?
We didn't do nothing wrong. Please, Miss
King, don't send us back to the
orphanage. If you make us go back there,
we'll only run away again.
What do you think?
Perhaps we should take a ride out to
Hillsdale.
No! No, not you.
Just Mr. McRae and I will go. You can
stay here with Cecily.
We'll speak to the matron and see if we
can straighten things out.
Oh, poor children.
I cannot imagine growing up without a
mother and father.
My mother died when I was 13.
They sent me off to boarding school.
What about your father?
Oh, he was busy managing his money. I
saw him on vacations. I received a
written by his secretary twice a year,
Christmas and my birthday.
Then when I was old enough, I struck out
on my own.
You know, I don't ever remember sitting
around the kitchen table enjoying a meal
with him like we did today.
Come inside and I'll take down the
particulars.
Someone can go and get them when we're
done.
But you see, they're all scared to death
to come back here again.
They're terribly distressed and we'd
like to know why.
It's that Belle Marie. She's a bad
influence on the others, but that's
I'll ship her out of here so far she'll
never see them again. Please don't do
that.
All she wants is for the family to stay
together. Can't you consider her
feelings? Oh, you're one of those, are
you?
Nobody's going to adopt her. And nobody
in their right mind will take the four
of them.
The best thing I can do for them is to
separate them and get them out of here
fast as I can.
You're wrong. We can get them out much
faster.
Come on, Stuart.
Wait, we haven't settled this.
Oh, yes, we have.
Here you go, Duffy.
You know how with me and Dora, it was
nip and tuck all the way before Marilla
adopted us.
We thought we were goners for sure.
Yeah, then Marilla died.
And Mrs. Lynn took us in.
Now we got Miss King looking out for us,
too.
We've been real lucky.
I'll say.
Nobody ever tried to separate you two?
Ever? Say, better not.
Davey's the only brother I've got.
or is he going to look after four
children?
Maybe he was wrong to raise their hopes.
It's providential, Father.
The Deans need a place to live.
Lloyd's house is empty, so we thought we
would make it into a family home.
Oh, a family.
Now, Felicity, charitable notions are
all well and good, dear, but it ought to
be an enormous undertaking.
Who, for example, will run the place?
I will.
With Stuart's help, of course.
I assume the two of you have discussed
this carefully.
We have, sir.
These poor children have been shunted
from pillar to post since their parents
died.
We feel it's the only choice.
Well, the house has to be fixed up, of
course.
Hold on, hold on, you two.
You don't get to make a decision like
this on your own, you know.
It's up to the town.
Aunt Hedy, we haven't forgotten.
And that is why Stuart has called
another meeting for tonight.
We hope that you'll all be there because
every vote is absolutely crucial.
But where's the money coming from?
Do you think that dollar bills grow on
trees?
The bank will cover any loans, Mrs.
Potts, interest -free. And then what?
Every scrawny little stray for miles
around will show up, and we'll be
with children. Then what do we do?
We take them in, of course.
How would you like your own children to
be abandoned like the deans?
Well, how would any of us like it?
What are they going to live on, all
these kids?
Air? What about food? What about
clothing?
I can't believe the people are reacting
like this.
Heaven's sake!
What's wrong with all of you?
As if a town like this can't clothe and
feed some poor, hungry little souls.
Well... I suppose it's better to give
than to receive.
I'll pledge $10 for a new roof.
Who'll throw in another ten?
Why, you old skinflint. Stuff your ten.
I'll put a roof on for free.
There's a spillet, and the ladies,
they'll paint and decorate.
Won't we, Olivia?
And the general store will collect
material for the curtains.
I'll scrounge up old pots and pans from
the hotel.
And the knights of P .E .I. will provide
whatever labor is necessary.
Shall we have a show of hands, then? All
those in favor of the Avonlea Foundling
Hall? Aye.
Opposed?
The eyes have at the motion.
Put the cook and clean and sleep there.
Those children can't stay alone in that
big old house.
I know that, Mother.
I'm moving in with them.
Let's see.
Are you sure you want to take on all
that responsibility?
Yes.
Oh, but... Let her do it.
It's the best medicine in the world.
Good job.
All right, everyone.
It's time for hot chocolate and then a
story.
And then the boys will go back to their
own room.
Callie, into bed.
All right.
Mother used to read to us before we went
to bed when we were children.
So I brought one of my favorites.
David Copperfield.
Chapter one.
I am born.
Whether I shall be the hero of my own
life or the station will be held by
else, these pages must show.
To begin my life with the beginning of
my life, I record that I was born, as I
have been informed and believe, on a
Friday at 12 o 'clock at night.
Hallie?
Whatever is the matter?
Like we've died and gone to heaven.
But I'm scared that something terrible
will happen.
And that you'll send us away.
And we'll never see you again.
Oh, sweetheart.
It's all right.
You're safe now, all of you.
This is your home.
You're not going anywhere. You have my
word.
I'm sure she'll be fine.
What if it rains? I mean, it could. It
could rain.
Yeah, there is that leaky roof.
I'd be worried about her all alone in
that spooky old house with four little
children.
She'll be fine.
Do we really need to haul all these
cakes and pies?
I mean, the... Sorry.
Heaven forbid the children should get
hungry.
I'll be right out.
I hope you don't mind, but I just wanted
to know that you and the children were
all right.
That's very kind of you.
Well, now that I know that everything's
fine, I guess I'd better be going.
I was just making some tea.
Would you like to have a cup?
Well, I don't think I should.
Stuart McRae, if I didn't know better,
I'd think you were afraid to be alone
with me.
My dear girl.
You may not care a whit about your
reputation, but my reputation and the
reputation of my bank may depend on this
cup of tea if Eulalie Bugle's lurking
out in those bushes.
If anyone is lurking in the bushes at
this hour, it's probably a chipmunk or a
rabbit, not Eulalie Bugle.
Oh, if he isn't, I'm sure about it. I'm
just doing wonderfully, dear.
Eulalie.
Eulalie. What's this?
Eulalie Bugle, are you there?
Mr. McRae is paying a call on publicity.
and probably was checking on the leaky
roof.
Roof? My auntie.
Are you kidding? That's charming.
Well, I'll be darned.
Well, maybe we should just, uh, you
know, move around there, sneak around,
out things, just to... A king will do no
such thing.
I trust my daughter.
Well, so do I.
Stuart McRae is a fine, settled
gentleman.
Only that he could do a lot worse.
Wait,
where are you going?
So why did we lug all this stuff
away from the wood?
Let me help you.
Oh, thank you.
Do you plan to stay in Avonlea, Stuart?
Oh, for the time being. I like it here.
I've had other offers, bigger towns,
bigger banks, but Avonlea suits me.
What about you?
Thank you.
Oh, well, I don't like to plan for the
future.
I think it's best to just live moment to
moment.
These last few days with the Dean
children have been the happiest I've
experienced in quite a while.
Me too.
The heavenly foundling home.
Perhaps this is what I was destined to
do.
Maybe one day it will be full of
children.
You're an unusual girl, Felicity King.
Tell me about Gus Pike.
What's there to tell, really?
For months, I dreamed that I would see
him again.
His ship would come sailing over the
horizon and there would be Gus standing
the bow waving at me.
I'm beginning to believe that that's not
going to happen.
What about you?
Me?
I'm just a crotchety old bachelor who's
devoted far too much of his life to
furthering his career.
I hope that will change.
It's, um, late.
Thank you for the tea and the company.
Good evening.
Felicity.
Can I call on you again?
That is, if it's not too...
Uncomfortable.
Difficult for me.
I know.
What I'm hoping is it will get easier.
Good night.
What they were buying in there,
everything but the kitchen sink. I tell
those orphans are eating them out of
house and home. And guess who's going to
have to pick up the bill? The rest of
us, that's who.
We're going on a little picnic, are we?
And we're going to eat choke of horse.
So I see.
Thank you.
Good day, ladies.
Good day, Mr.
McRae.
What do you make of that?
Paying an awful lot of attention to
Felicity King these days.
That won't last long, mark my words.
She's one of those girls takes a light
in the widow's wings.
Bye. Have a nice time, everybody.
Bye.
Mr.
King, do you have a minute?
Yes, I do.
Good, because there's something I wanted
to say about Felicity.
I want you and Mrs. King to know that my
intentions are completely honorable.
I intend to ask for her hand in
marriage. I want your approval first.
Well... Um... Well, Mr. McRae, the...
Stuart.
Of course, Stuart.
Well, you must know that Janet and I
like you very much.
Good. That's a good thing.
But...
Are you sure that Felicity and you...
Well, hello in here.
Is something wrong?
Oh, no, nothing's wrong. In fact, Mr.
Stewart here was just asking... Well, he
wants to ask Felicity
to marry him.
Oh, my heavens.
Oh, well...
Of course, we give you our blessing.
Oh, Alec, isn't this a most wonderful
surprise?
Oh, Mrs. King, I'm greatly heartened.
She's a wonderful girl, and if she'll
me, I'll take good care of her always.
Oh, no, don't run.
You stay and have a bite to eat.
Oh, no, I couldn't.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Forgive me.
I just couldn't eat a thing.
Lord, Janet, I don't know about this.
Oh, Halleck, what are you talking about?
You yourself said Felicity's the
happiest she's been in months.
Now, that is because of Stuart McRae.
He's brought her out of the dole rooms
where the rest of us failed miserably.
Yes, I know, but still... Halleck,
what's wrong with you?
Our daughter's safely married to a fine
young man whose head overhears in love
with her.
You should be on top of the world.
Except he isn't Gus Pike.
Not by a long shot.
Felix!
Couldn't help it, Mother. I heard the
whole thing.
You shouldn't have encouraged him
without asking Felicity first.
Felix, I will thank you, young man, to
keep your opinions to yourself.
I know Felicity, and she wouldn't fall
in love with him, not in a million
Felix King, I do not want you throwing
cold water over your sister's happiness.
Says she's happy.
Have you asked her?
I'm just saying he's not the man Gus
Pike was.
I feel like that's enough.
There's so much that we have to do. The
children haven't really had any proper
schooling, so I thought that we would
speak to Aunt Hedy and see if she can
them some early lessons that they can
catch up. Felicity, I need to talk to
about us.
You must know how I feel.
Gut was only a memory I'm hearing now.
Stop. I don't want to hear this.
Be practical, Felicity.
You can't cling to a ghost forever.
Stop it.
Leave me alone.
King Edgar took my jacket. Did not.
Liar, liar. Pants on fire.
Felicity.
Felicity? Felicity, go home for the
night.
You need a rest from all of this.
I'll take care of the children.
Felix was right.
I shouldn't have encouraged him, but...
Really, dear, did you have to be so
final? Mother, he's one of the finest
I've ever met.
I only want what's best for you.
Felicity, dear, a first love is just
that, the first.
But Gus is gone.
Please, don't let that first love be
your last.
You're saying that I should forget Gus?
No, no. I'm saying that caring for
somebody else is not going to
banish Gus from your heart.
forgive me for yesterday i shouldn't
have said the things that i did i love
i would have taken you on any terms all
i wanted was for
you to be happy
I thought you might want to ride back to
the family home.
What's this?
It's our wish box.
You and me and Sarah, remember?
It was so long ago.
I was going to open it, but I thought I
should ask you first.
How old was I?
Nine, I think.
Well, go ahead. Open it.
Listen to this.
I wish I could have all the wishes I
want, but if I can't have that, I wish I
could have a million dollars so I could
move far away from my miserable sister,
Felicity.
Sorry, I was just a kid.
It's all right.
I suppose that was pretty awful.
I wish I could marry a man
as strong and kind as my father.
A man who will love me forever and ever.
I wish for a white wedding and six
children.
Dreams, Felix.
Where did they go?
My dear Felicity.
I am leaving Avonlea on today's train to
seek other employment.
I hope my forwardness has not caused you
grief.
I never meant to harm your good name.
My intention... Life goes on,
sweetheart.
And it will for you, too, if you just
let it. Don't let that first love be
last. I love you.
All I wanted was you to be happy.
All right, uh...
Stuart!
Stuart, wait!
Please don't go.
i don't know what i want i don't even
know what i'm saying all i
know is that i'm begging you not to
leave